The true story of how the world's most popular team rose from the ashes
United is a drama, history film directed by James Strong.
United is based on the true story of Manchester United's legendary "Busby Babes", the youngest side ever to
win the Football League and the 1958 Munich Air Crash that claimed eight of the their number.
The film draws on first-hand interviews with the survivors and their families to tell the
inspirational story of a team and community overcoming terrible tragedy.
Jimmy Murphy, played by David Tennant.
Bobby Charlton, played by Jack O'Connell.
Duncan Edwards, played by Sam Claflin.
Matt Busby, played by Dougray Scott.
Bert Whalley, played by Dean Andrews.
Alma George, played by Kate Ashfield.
United is a British television film directed by James
Strong and written by Chris Chibnall.
It is based on the true story of Manchester United's "Busby Babes" and the aftermath of the 1958
Munich air disaster, with the film's events taking place between August 1956 and May 1958.
In particular, the film focuses on the experiences of assistant manager Jimmy Murphy,
played by David Tennant, and Bobby Charlton, played by Jack O'Connell.
Largely filmed around the North East of England, the film was first broadcast on 24 April 2011 on BBC
Two and BBC HD, and sold internationally as a theatrical picture by Content Media Corp.
The series gained a 14.3% rating in its time slot and was
generally well received by television critics.
The film explores themes of airplane crash, football
(soccer), historical event, sports documentary.
The tone is emotional.